# Danilo **Diaz** Machine Learning Engineer

♥ Dig 56 No 21a-04, Bello , Antioquia, Colombia

i 03 September 1994 (27 years)

I am experienced data engineer with good interpersonal and professional skills, hand on attitude and high self-initiative. In my work I am goal oriented and disciplined and constantly strive to explore new technologies. My strengths are machine learning, Python, NumPy, Pandas, TensorFlow, Pyspark, Azure, SQL, Mongo DB, API REST and Scikit-learn.

I have good leadership skills and I enjoy working in multicultural environment and working in a team. I am good in handling different situations, challenging tasks and working under pressure worker. I am an innovation lover and a quick learner.



#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Ongoing March 2021

#### Machine Learning Engineer Intermediate, MEDELLIN, InterGrupo

- > Developing Machine Learning algorithms.
- > Deploying ML models to production using MLOps
- > Support clients as an expert to propose the best solution to problems.
- > Perform constant review of implemented models.
- > Support the MLe Senior in the implementation of simulations, deployments, code refactoring.

Python Azure PySpark MongoDB FastApi SQL

# March 2021 April 2019

## Project Engineer and Data scientist, MEDELLIN, Logistica y ATP

- > Developing model algorithms for logistics application.
- > Estimating the duration and costs of projects.
- > Analyzing customer data to propose efficient solutions that improve processes along the supply chain.
- > Developing and maintaining Warehouse design

Python Pyspark E-Commerce SQL

### March 2019 March 2018

#### Coordinator of Application Engineering, Medellin, Colplast S.A.S.

- > Formulated, designed and controlled the projects of the sub-management for the development, implementation, testing, and production concerning plastics transformation.
- > Determined the scope of the project together with technicians and engineers, to establish the activities and resources required for its successful completion.

Python Project

# March 2018 August 2017

# Mechanical Maintenance and Project Engineer, MEDELLIN, Plastiquimia S.A.S

- > I created an Excel and Python program capable for anticipating the company energy cost per machine.
- > I created several applications that help with the maintenance and management in Excel.
- > Developed detailed 3D modeling using Solidworks, Auto Rhinoceros.

Python Oracle DB SQL Excel

# September 2012 January 2014

# Mould and die design apprentice, MEDELLIN, TECNOMEC S.A.S

- > 3D modeling and detailed engineering in CAD programs (Solidworks and Auto Rhinoceros).
- > Programming macros and applications in Excel.

Python Excel SQL Solidworks

#### faLaptop



### **EDUCATION**

2020-2021 Specialization (Data Analyst - GPA: 4.8) - Universidad de Antioquia

2012-2016 Bachelor's Degree (Mechanical Engineer - GPA: 4.2) - EAFIT University

2015-2016 Academic vocational training (Integrated design of technical systems) - EAFIT University



Programmation Python (Pandas, Numpy, Pyspark, Jupyter), TensorFlow, Scikit-learn

Frameworks Fast Api , Django , Django - REST

DataBases MongoDB, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL

**Cloud Computing** Azure (intermediate), AWS(Beginner)

Development tools Visual Studio Code, Git

Operating systems Windows 10, Linux

# PROJETS

POSTOBON CCV 2021 - ONGOING

Postobon CCV

We have developed 3 big ML algorithm to support 3 operations of Postobon(company of alcoholic and non-alcoholic beverages). **Model Prices** Estimated the best material price of a product for a specific zone. **Model Promotions** Estimated the best promotion for a client. **Model Negotiations** Estimated the best negotiation for a client.

Machine Learning Azure Python Visual Studio Code Git FastApi

#### ACTIVE MEMBER OF A MACHINE LEARNING STUDY GROUP

2018 - 2021

☑ MachineLearningColombia

The objective of the group is to ensure that its members obtained an advanced level in machinelearning knowledge and to develop innovative projects in the city.

Facebook Python Visual Studio Code

#### DEMAND FORECASTING IN WAREHOUSES WITH MACHINE LEARNING

2019 - 2021

Logistica v ATP

I have developed machine learning models to predict product's demand and picking times, toimprove the processes inside the warehouse.

Machine Learning | AWS | Python | Visual Studio Code

#### DEVELOPING BOM WITH SOL AND EXCEL.

2017 - 2018

Plastiquimica

I have created BOM- A bill of materials app, for planning production, where explosion displays an assembly at the highest level broken down into single components and parts at the lowest level.

Excel Python Visual Studio Code Numpy Pandas

## A ROBOTIC SYSTEM CAPABLE OF POURING DRINKS TO ITS USER

2015 - 2016

☑ EAFIT

I developed Robot Prototype that performs tasks such as pouring drinks in collaboration with a built-in camera which creates a supplying live vision of the surroundings. The project goal was fully defined as a robotic prototype that can mimic some waiter's tasks using artificial vision, inverse kinematics and control the pump of the liquor's flow.

Facebook Python Visual Studio Code

# **7** Course & Certifications

2021 AZ 900 - Microsoft

2021 FastApi and Python MLops - Udemy

2020 Introduction to Data Science in Python Coursera

2020 Platzi Courses - Platzi





 > English English Level : Advanced : C1 KI, Vancouver

> IELTS 6.5

# 66 RÉFÉRENCES

# Kattia Benedetti Padrón

HR Manager, LAMITECH

@ kbenedetti@lamitech.com.co

+57 315 718 7717

### Jaime Barbosa

Professor, Universidad EAFIT

@ jbarbosa@eafit.edu.co

+33 1 23 45 67 90